sgs.com 2018-04-03

# Privacy Policy | SGS

The SGS Group companies take the security and privacy of their contacts about which they hold information seriously. The purpose of this policy is to describe to you the information we may hold about you, explain what we use it for, and explain your rights in relation to it. By visiting any SGS Group company website, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

### What information do we collect? 

In general, you can access and consult any SGS Website without disclosing or revealing any personal information about yourself. 

However, in order to better provide you with products and services, certain SGS Group company websites may collect one or both of the following types of information from you: Personally Identifiable Information and Non-Personally Identifiable Information. 

**Personally Identifiable Information refers** to information that lets us know the specifics of who you are. Personal information is requested when you order a service, register for an account and send us feedback. For example, this information might include your name, address (both billing and registered), email address, industry and product details, and credit card or other payment information. Such information may be held on our contacts and administration databases either because of the work we have done with you or are currently engaged in, or because we believe you might be interested in receiving material from us about our business and services. This allows us to manage our relationship with you efficiently, improve our Website and the services which we offer to you and to target items of interest we may send to you. 

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information** refers to information that is statistical in nature only and that does not, by itself, identify a specific individual or entity, and which depends upon the visiting you do on the SGS Group company websites. For example, this information may include the domain from which you access the Internet, the date and time you access any SGS Group company website, and the Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to any SGS Group company website. This information is used in an aggregate form to make the SGS Group company websites more useful and attractive to its users.

This website may also use, on some pages, the HotJar Analysis and Feedback tool. The HotJar service helps us analyze how visitors use our websites. It reveals the online behavior and feedback of our website's visitors. By combining both A) Analysis and B) Feedback tools, Hotjar gives us the 'big picture' of how to improve our website visitor’s experience and the site’s performance. We do not collect through the HotJar service or transfer to HotJar any Personal Identifiable Information. We only use the HotJar service to record, for some visitors on some websites and on a completely anonymous basis, information such as mouse clicks, mouse movements, scrolling activity as well as non-Personally Identifiable Information text you type in some of our websites. Information about the browser (type, version, screen size, etc.), basic information about the user (IP address, language, time zone) and data containing mouse movements, clicks, scroll events and keystrokes are sent to HotJar. No personal data is sent. Hotjar uses a variety of services hosted by third parties, such as Google Analytics and Optimizely. These services may collect information sent by your browser as part of a web page request, such as cookies or your IP request. For information on how Google Analytics and Optimizely collect and use your information, please refer to their privacy policies. Keystrokes from password fields and fields marked as “sensitive” are never recorded or sent over the network. For more information see HotJar’s Privacy Policy at <https://www.hotjar.com/privacy>. You can choose to disable the HotJar service at <https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out>.

### Does SGS share the information it receives?

Information about our clients is an important part of our business and SGS is not in the business of selling it to others. We share personally identifiable information only as set forth below:

  1. By transfer to other SGS Group companies where it is necessary to meet the purpose for which you have submitted the information. By submitting data on any SGS Group company website, you are providing explicit consent to trans-border transmission of data collected on that website. 
  2. By transfer to third party agents and subcontractors which perform certain functions on behalf of SGS, such as picking up and delivering samples, fulfilling inspection orders, sending email, removing repetitive information from client lists, analysing data and processing credit card payments. These parties only have access to such information as necessary to perform their functions and may not use it for any other purpose. 
  3. For any reason if, in SGS' sole discretion, SGS believes it is reasonable to do so, including: to satisfy any laws, regulations, or governmental or legal requests for such information; to disclose information that is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating our Terms of Access or other terms and conditions; or to otherwise protect the SGS Group of companies.

### How does SGS protect your information?

We follow strict security procedures in the storage and disclosure of information which you have given us in order to prevent unauthorised access. However, the SGS site contains links to other websites. SGS does not control and is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these other websites.

"Cookies" and how SGS uses them   

### Your rights

Regarding the information held about you by SGS, you may, for example, request us to provide you with a list and a description of this information, request us to amend any inaccuracies, or notify us that you do not consent to our continued use of this information by contacting us in the manner set out below.

We also welcome questions and your comments about our data protection policy.

### How to contact us

At any time using one of the methods below:

(i) by  emailing us

(ii) by faxing us: + 41 22 739 98 61

(iii) by writing to us: SGS Société Générale de Surveillance SA, 1, place des Alpes, P.O. Box 2152, CH-1211 Geneva 1, Switzerland.

(iv) by calling us: + 41 22 739 91 11

SGS continually strives to improve its service to its customers and to its potential customers.

Page last modified on February 5, 2016
